SUMIT KUMAR MBA(Finance) CA (Inter), B.Com(H) Email: sharma.sumit2080@gmail.com

Mob No. +919873429141

PROFILE

Job Title : Accounts, Taxation & Audit

Objective : Contribute to an ambitious organization where my potential

Can be explored to its best and my efforts are rewarded.

Qualification : MBA(Finance & HR), CA(Inter) & B.Com(H) with 5 yrs+

Experience in Accounts, Taxation & Administration.

PERSONALITY TRAITS:

• Good Listener and solution provider.

- Ability to coach team members.
- Loves taking on new challenges and lead from the front.
- Strong Communication and inter-personal skills.
- Adapt a structured approach

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:

YEAR OF QUALIFYING	NAME OF EXAMINATION PASSED	NAME OF THE BOARD/UNIVERSITY/ INSTITUTION
2018	MBA(Finance & HR)	Swami Vivekanand Shubharti University,
		Meerut(UP)
2012	CA (Inter)	The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India,
		Delhi
2008	B.COM (Hons.)	Magadh University, Gaya (Bihar)

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY:

- Proficient on internet, email &e-filing of various statutory forms/returns
- Working knowledge of MS-office (excel, word, PowerPoint etc.),
- Efficient in working with Tally ERP 9, Computax (ITRs & TDS) taxation software
- Completed 250Hrs. Compulsory Computer Training (CCT) conducted by ICAI

WORK EXPERIENCE:

<u>Organisation</u> <u>Designation</u>

Brajmohan Singh & Associates
From Feb 2017 to till date

• Credible Professional Services Pvt. Ltd. From Jan 2012 to Jan 2017.

 M/S D. Lal Chopra & Co. (Chartered Accountants)
From March 2008 to Sept. 2011 Working As a Team Leader

Worked As an Accountant

Worked As an Article Assistant

WORK PROFILE:

ACCOUNTING & BOOK KEEPING:

- Finalization of financial reports (Balance Sheet, P&L A/c, Cash flow, Etc.)
- Maintaining books of accounts on day to day basis as per applicable standards
- Preparing monthly and annual reports
- Complying TDS & GST requirements
- Resolved queries and maintained closed interaction with different business units

TAXATION

- Income Tax returns, computations and E-Filing (Individual, Firms, Trust, Companies).
- Form 15CA, 15CB etc
- TDS matters including eTDS returns.
- GST matters registrations, returns and issuance of statutory forms and assessment.

AUDIT

- Statutory Audit & Internal Audit : ICICI Bank Ltd.
- Stock Audit of Big Bazar, Snap Deal, Big Apple, Relince Etc.
- Salary & Wages Audit of Snap Deal
- Physical Verification of Fixed Assets TITEN Watch
- Contributed to finalise all types of audits i.e. Internal, Tax as well as Statutory Audit.
- Finalized Balance Sheets of all type (Corporate as well as Non corporate) of allotted clients

ROC

- Incorporated more than 50 companies including OPC & LLP
- Annual Filling of accounts
- Changes of Name, Registered Office, Increase in Capital, alteration in Main Object, Changes in Directors & Transfer of share
- Closure of Company
- Other ROC related compliances

PERSONEL DETAILS:

Name: Sumit Kumar Date of Birth: 05/12/1988

Father's Name: Dr. Vishwanath Sharma

Current Address: S – 611C, 2nd Floor, Nehru Enclave, School Block, Shakarpur,

New Delhi – 110092.

Permanent Address: Infront of Eastern Gate Of D.M. Residence, Gaya,

Bihar – 823001.

Date: -

Place: - New Delhi SUMIT KUMAR